Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The battle of Solomon had come to an end.
The Space Attack Force,
commanded by Vice Admiral Dozle...
...was effectively obliterated.
It was a defeat that the Principality of Zeon
had been unable to anticipate.
Sovereign Degwin Zabi...
...is said to have told Gihren that
this should have been expected of Dozle.
While containing his anger
against the Sovereign...
...Gihren made a declaration
to the ranks of Zeon's high officials.
He would use the stronghold
of A Baoa Qu as the final line of defense...
...and defeat the Federation.
The Duel in Texas
Nothing to report
within the second battle line.
No enemy vessels... no mines.
It's a good thing.
We're switching in 30 minutes, okay?
Amuro is here now.
Please check his blood pressure for me.
Right.
Oscar, Marker, and Amuro
are all holding up well.
It must be hard with all the things
they're asking you to do, Fraw Bow.
It's nothing compared to what you're doing.
How long has it been?
Since when?
Since the two of us stopped talking.
Well, we've been so preoccupied.
Yeah.
The computer analysis says you're healthy.
Amuro... You've become so strong, it's scary.
Huh?
You're far beyond my reach now.
But that's fine.
I don't want to see you being weak, and...
We all have to grow up like this.
S-Sorry... Fraw Bow... I didn't mean to...
Don't worry, it's okay...
But... did something happen at Side 6?
It seems you've changed, Amuro.
Do you really think so?
It's not like...
I'll tell you someday,
when I figure out what to say.
A lot happened there.
Oh...
How is he?
Perfectly healthy.
How is Hayato coming along?
He's right on track,
thanks to his athletic background.
That's a problem...
It's the Texas shoal zone region.
Should we wake everyone up?
Oh! Sorry to wake you.
That's okay.
There's a Chivvay at the edge
of the third combat line, but...
...there seem to be others in the Texas zone.
On a mopping-up operation of enemy
vessels that escaped from Solomon...
...the White Base enters the Texas zone.
It is a shoal zone filled with debris.
This colony was originally built
for leisure and raising livestock...
...and was named Texas.
It was abandoned due to
its lack of military significance.
It's now surrounded by drifting rocks
and colony debris.
Haven't the Elmeth and bits
been delivered to Texas yet?
The fine-tuning is taking some time.
Never mind.
At least my own Gelgoog has arrived.
Is there anyone here at Texas?
Well...
It seems there are some former workers
and staff at the colony's management office.
So the colony is practically uninhabited.
Yes.
What about the Trojan Horse?
M'Quve is nearby?
Yes.
We have no weapons on hand,
so let him deal with the enemy.
We'll be docking the Zanzibar at Texas.
The Chivvay is moving.
They've noticed us.
All right. Wake up the whole crew!
Enemy approaching!
All hands to level 3 battle stations!
It was such a nice bath, especially
after barely escaping with my life!
The enemy probably escaped from Solomon.
We'll launch the Guncannon
as soon as we reach the second battle area!
All hands, we may have survived
Solomon, but stay on guard!
Mirai. Are you okay?
I'm sorry for making you worry.
I'd like to work and get tired a little.
Don't overdo it.
I'm here for you, if you ever want to talk.
Thank you...
It's good to hear that.
It's just as I'd planned.
We've found the Trojan Horse.
Uragang! What's the status of my Gyan?
Sir! It's ready.
Good... Proceed now to Area Two,
then launch the Rick Doms!
I'll sortie with my Gyan.
But there's no reason you should
go out in person, Captain M'Quve.
Oh, yes there is.
Sir?
The mobile suit Gyan was developed
especially for me.
I must maintain my standing as a man
to Rear Admiral Kycilia.
Besides, I hear that Char still
hasn't received the mobile suit he requested.
I'll demolish the Trojan Horse
and the Gundam while he watches.
Ms. Sayla!
You should be able to locate the Chivvay
in the second battle area. Be careful!
Roger that!
Trojan Horse detected at Point 3-AA!
All hands to battle stations!
Rick Doms, make a preemptive strike
on the enemy fighter-bombers!
When you see the Gundam,
lure it into Texas.
That'll make it easier for the Gyan.
Yes, sir! We understand.
Good! Then move out!
Here they come... Ms. Sayla, the Chivvay!
It'll come into view soon!
Roger!
Marker, what are the enemy's movements?
It's hard to see through the debris.
Maximum magnification ahead!
Is the enemy after the G-Armor...?
Uragang! I'm counting on you
to stall the Trojan Horse!
It's just one ship,
but don't relax your guard!
Roger, Captain. All clear for takeoff, sir.
Do everything as per the plan.
I'll set a trap near Texas.
Remember, it's a two-rank promotion
if we defeat the Gundam.
They're coming, Amuro!
See that, Amuro?
Are there 4 or 5 mobile suits?
Thanks to the Minovsky particles
and all the rocks, it's hard to tell!
I see them!
Amuro, can you shoot them?
I'll give it a try.
Hurry and bolt out!
Roger!
Here it comes.
Where is he?
A Dom!
The Gundam and G-Fighter
are drifting toward Texas!
Kai! Standby to take off!
All hands to level 1 battle stations!
Petty Officer Sunmalo.
Has another battle begun?
Just concentrate on getting better, Hayato.
That's part of your duty, too.
I understand that, but my injuries
aren't as bad as we thought!
You'll be up and about in a couple of days,
so just rest up until then.
It's not easy to be a dashing hero, is it?
You look dashing as a healthy patient.
Don't make things difficult for me.
This colony's a sad sight
with its mirror adjustment problems...
Everything's dried up.
How's it going, Flanagan?
She's doing well. Lalah hit the test targets
with 70 percent accuracy.
I suppose we should return to the Zanzibar.
Here at the Texas colony,
built for cattle raising and leisure...
...the mirrors were damaged in the war,
and stopped working.
The colony has remained in twilight
for over 8 months.
The land has thus turned to desert,
and the people have moved away.
Something's coming.
What is it?
Coming here? What is?
I wonder what it is...
What am I sensing...?
Something's coming.
Flanagan! What is it?
It's not one of the test targets.
I've never seen her brain waves resonate
like this before.
Is there somebody like me around here?
Lalah. What did you just say?
It feels like you touched my heart, Captain.
I did what?
Lalah. Don't joke around.
Yes, sir.
But what was that?
That tingling sensation just now.
Those pilots are experienced!
But I can read their pattern!
Gundam and G-Fighter
have entered the Texas area!
What is the starboard fleet doing?
No changes. They're progressing slowly.
This is the last one.
What...?!
This whole thing was a scheme
to lure me toward this mobile suit...!
Now then...
Come to me... Gundam.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
You bastard...
Talk about devious...!
Yes, I did it!
That's what you get for expecting everyone
to fight fair and square, Gundam!
He's escaping into Texas?
What are you staring at?
At you, Captain. Does that bother you?
I don't mind.
Do you really think I can pilot the Elmeth?
Are you afraid?
Yes.
You'll just have to get used to it.
I'll always be by your side.
So you'll be a better pilot than me
in no time, Lalah.
Me?
Better than the Red Comet?
Of course.
Otherwise, I wouldn't have sent
an orphan like you to the Flanagan Institute.
I'm sorry I left you feeling lonely at Side 6.
Captain! Captain M'Quve has entered Texas
in his mobile suit.
M'Quve? How odd.
I never knew he had this side to him.
I hear he's had a mobile suit developed
for his own personal use...
...and he's sworn to bring down
the Trojan Horse. He must feel confident.
He's simply trying to spite me.
I can't think of any other reason
for him to do something so foolhardy.
Nonetheless...
we can't sit still and watch, either.
The Gelgoog's maintenance is finished.
It's a prototype, so it's hardly perfect, but...
Then this will double as a field test
while I keep an eye on M'Quve.
One more!
Finally...
Enemy vessels!
Fraw Bow! Send out the Guncannon!
Yes, sir!
How many vessels, Marker?
One Chivvay, two Musais!
What could that be?
I know. I've memorized the data
on the Gelgoog.
Won't you at least wear a normal suit?
It's my policy to come back
with my mobile suit in one piece.
I rely on my survival instinct.
That's why I never wear combat suits
or normal suits.
Take me up!
Yes, sir!
That's not it.
These small-scale bombs won't hurt me...!
Captain...!
Observe from a safe distance, Lalah.
This is a battle between mobile suits.
Yes.
Now then. Show me what you've got, M'Quve.
3... 2... 1... Go ahead!
The Baromel...!
Use those rocks to shield the ship!
Is that it?
Does he have good instincts,
or is he one of those new types of human?
A friendly mobile suit...?
He's good!
A red mobile suit...!
Is it Char?!
Char! Pull back!
It's not your mission
to defeat the Gundam right now!
I can't stand idly by
and ignore an ally in obvious trouble.
I have my own way of fighting!
That's why I lured the Gundam here!
I'll leave it to you, Captain M'Quve.
Look out!
I've confirmed it with the data I've collected.
You've used up too much beam energy
in your skirmish with Char!
Why you...!
I was hoping that the Gundam
would get rid of him for me.
But M'Quve's putting up a good fight...
Lalah, you're watching this, aren't you?
Why won't the Captain go and help out?
Why...?
This is the same thing I felt earlier!
Put your sword away!
Your dirty tricks are no match
against Gundam's power!
In order to put Char in his place...
...I have to defeat the Gundam!
What the...?!
Stop already. It's over.
Huh?! What...?
Uragang! Deliver that antique vase
to Lady Kycilia!
It's priceless!
Just as I expected.
So hastily prepared, you can't fight!
Captain!
Who is it...?
Somebody's watching me...
This feeling...
It isn't Char...
This is...
A... mu... ro...?
La... lah...?
For Amuro, who is on the verge
of acquiring a new strength...
...Char poses virtually no threat.
As the fierce battle continues,
Sayla asks Char in earnest...
Will he leave Zeon behind
and finally return to her?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Char and Sayla.
Will you be able to survive?
Next Time
Char and Sayla
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...